Shijia Zheng

Phone: 516 300 2688

E-mail: shijiazheng725@gmail.com github.com/shijiazheng123

Skills

- Python
- Javascript / NodeJS
- Scal
- (
- C#
- Linux
- MySQL
- X-query
- Unit Testing
- Web Development
 - HTML / CSS
 - AJAX
 - React/React Native
 - HTTP / HTTPS
 - WebSockets
 - Django
 - Flask
 - Wordpress

- REST APIs
- Docker
- Microsoft Office
- Adobe CC
- Processing
- Phaser JS
- Unity
- Computer Security
- Graphic Design
 - Web Design
 - UI/UX Design
 - Print Design
 - Logo Design
 - Digital Illustration
- Data Entry
- Mandarin Chinese

Projects

Dynamic Memory Allocator

Developed with C. Recreated a dynamic memory allocator similar to C's malloc().

Social Media Site

Developed with Javascript, Python, and Django. A social media site focusing on full-stack development. Worked with a group to create a site with user accounts, authentication, real-time feed updates, post voting, and direct messaging.

Story Sharing Site

Developed with React and a REST API developed by Prof. Hunt. A site that focuses on frontend development and UI/UX design. Worked with a group to create a site that allowed users to share stories, and allow other users to write continuations to the shared story, featuring a voting system that determines the best continuation to append to the story.

Education

University at Buffalo Buffalo, NY Computer Science B.A. Game Studies Certificate Graduating in 2021 GPA 3.8

Relevant Coursework

- Systems Programming
- Data Structures
- Web Applications
- Applied Human-Computer Interaction
- Computer Security
- Data Models and Query Language
- Computer Systems Administration

Awards/Honors

Dean's List

Work Experience

React Developer - OneDataShare

August 2020-Present

Worked on the team of an NSF research project known as One-DataShare. Developed and designed the front-end of OneDataShare's website to be user friendly and responsive for mobile views using React and Material-UI

Web Development Intern -

Technical Consulting and Research, Inc.

June 2020 - September 2020

Developed the front-end of the company's website to be user friendly and responsive for mobile views

Teaching Assistant -

University at Buffalo

January 2021 - Present

Assisted students in the Web Applications course in developing skills needed for web development programming

Bookkeeper, Machine Setup, Customer Service -

MCP Solutions

June 2012 - July 2016, May 2018-August 2018

Managed bills and kept financial records and receipts for the company; set up financial machinery for clients; took customer support calls and assisted with customer questions and concerns

Art Director - Short Film: "Overcome"

January 2017 - April 2017

Designed sets for film scenes, created practical effects, and managed the prop budget through coordination with the executive producer

Logo Designer - Ottonomous Productions January 2018

Redesigned the studio's logo through coordination and communication with the marketing department